Peter Kimeli



kimelipeter20@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/peter-kimeli-7a59b2155



+254708995320



https://kimpetertanui.github.io/

Summary

Talented DevOps Engineer/Software Developer with over four years of enterprise in software and mobile development and a broad range of industries including News Media, Mobile Payments, B2B, Restaurant Management, Integrated Commerce and Banking. Solid understanding of full mobile and Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including Waterfall and Agile methodologies. Well conversant with version control including CVS, SVN, Gitlab and Git. Android experience and Expertise. Dedicated to continuously developing, implementing, and adopting new technologies to maximize development efficiency and produce innovative applications.

Messaging frameworks.RabbitMQ,Apache Kafka and Apache Pusar, monitoring tool: Prometheus; Devops tools: Jenkins, Gitlab CI/CD, Docker,Kubernetes,

Experience



DevOps Engineer

Safaricom PLC

Aug 2021 - Present (6 months +)

Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment

Built and deployed Docker containers to break up monolithic app into microservices,

improving developer workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed

Automate build and deployment using Jenkins to reduce human error and speed up production processes

Help scale our platform for better customer experience.

Improve deployment process within AWS

Scripting: Shell, Python

Improve automated test and simulation frameworks in the pipeline.

Develop and automate standard operating procedures around common failure scenarios.

Monitor, analyze, and report performance statistics for cloud hosted environments.

Develop application performance management to measure and act upon performance data.

Participate in an on-call schedule in the local timezone.

Write clean, well-documented, and resilient code.



Software Engineer

Adalabs Africa

Jun 2020 - Aug 2021 (1 year 3 months)

Worked individually as well as part of a larger team on developing and maintaining multiple client applications

Contributed to full life cycle development of eCOBba App

Extensive use and implementation of the Google Places API (JSON), PayPal OAuth 2.0,

Worked on multiple emulators to thoroughly develop and test deployment and interoperability on multiple platforms

Documented architecture and implementation for internal and external consumption

Implemented support for applications using Flickr API, Google Maps API, Facebook API, and Twitter AP

Windows/ Ubuntu system administration and performance tuning

Experience with Amazon CLI, EC2, S3, CloudFront

Automation skills with Puppet

Jenkins

Docker, Vagrant

Web stack (Nginx, PHP-fpm)

Git and Gitlab

Shell, Python scripting

Working knowledge of data frameworks: Hadoop architecture and its ecosystem, Apache Spark,

Apache Flume, Apache sqoop, Apache pig, Hive, data warehousing;

Messaging frameworks.RabbitMQ,Apache Kafka and Apache Pusar,

monitoring tool: Prometheus;

Devops tools: Jenkins, Gitlab CI/CD, Docker

Android Developer

Mobitechtechnologies

Mar 2019 - May 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Senior Android Developer

Implemented features for various applications in Java, Kotlin, and C++.

Determined architectural and product design details for open-ended tasks or specifications.

Collaborated with quality engineers, user research, product management, design, and support teams to ensure quality in all phases of app development.

Worked closely with core technology teams and other platform teams to balance cross-platform consistency with Android-optimization.

Wrote elegant, self-documenting code, easy to read and adapt for other developers.

Reviewed design specs and engineering docs and provide feedback.

Key achievements:

Created and tested 25+ Android apps and games that brought in about \$300K within a 6-month period.

Integrated third party libraries including Picasso and ActionBarSherlock

Implemented Clean Architecture using Dagger2 nad RxJava.

Used specific code versioning tools to manage and implement changes to programs.



Senior Software Engineer

EldoHub Innovation

Jan 2018 - Feb 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Adopted engineering best practices and delivered highest quality scalable solutions.

Paired with fellow engineers to brainstorm ideas, debug problems and review code.

Designed and implemented scalable application programming interfaces.

Delivered documentation for design decisions, estimating assumptions, code modules and performance metrics.

Understood full technology stack and underlying applications, services and databases, resulting in optimal program performance.

Worked with customers to define requirements and troubleshoot issues and architected and implemented new engineering applications to meet needs.

Created and maintained service desk diagnostics and job aids and reviewed with technicians to confirm clarity.

Performed development, debugging, optimization and automation to support implementation of products and applications.

Developed complex software and systems deploying one or more programming languages.

Followed and supported change management practices and internal controls standards.

Developed e-commerce website to reduce cart abandonment rate by40%, resulting in increased online sales after go-live date.

Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.

Boosted web traffic by improving navigation and rectifying bottlenecks.

Spearheaded production of page content such as visuals and text copy to meet project specifications. Owned more than 5 projects per year from initial research and conceptual design through testing and implementation phases.

Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.

Crafted SEO strategy and intuitive interface for site to achieve prominent rankings across top browser platforms.

Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.

Built user interface, data visualizations and designed overall user experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales.

Education

DEDAN KIMATHI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (DeKUT)

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2015 - 2019

Licenses & Certifications

- in Agile Foundations LinkedIn
- DevOps with AWS LinkedIn
- in Scrum: The Basics LinkedIn
- in Stay Lean with Kanban LinkedIn
- in Design Thinking: Understanding the Process (2016) LinkedIn
- in Learning AWS CloudFormation LinkedIn

Skills

Microsoft Office • Research • Project Management • Customer Service • Microsoft Excel • Management • Leadership • Strategic Planning • Microsoft Word • Project Planning